Mss.Ms.Coll.95 Mss.Ms.Coll.95
American Philosophical Society
- Series I. Correspondence (Box 1-18)
  - Rodrigues, Aryon D., 1996; 2 items (Box 13)
    Obtaining copies of recordings and notes that FGL might have of the Umutina language.
  - Romney, A. Kimball, 1962; 4 items (Box 13)
    A conference on "Transcultural Studies of Cognitive Systems" in Merida, Yucatan.
  - Rood, David S., 1981; 2 items (Box 13)
    A complimentary subscription to IJAL for FGL.
  - Roots, Edward Brian, 1990; 2 items (Box 13)
    An Osage vocabulary collected by William Nathan Belcher. Includes photocopies of the vocabulary.
  - Rosenheck, Charles, 1956; 2 items (Box 13)
    The origin of human language.
  - Rosenthal, Elizabeth C., 1971-1989; 3 items (Box 13)
    Finding a position working to help Native Americans; attending the funeral of "...our old friend Harry."
  - Rosenthal, Julius, Art Slides, 1951; 4 items (Box 13)
    FGL's order for slides of Australian aboriginal art.
  - Rossi, Franco, 1992; 2 items (Box 13)
    Availability of learning aids for Oneida, Onondaga, and Tuscarora.
  - Rothenberg, Martin, 1964; 2 items (Box 13)
    Materials for teaching the interpretation of speech spectrograms.
  - Rouse, Irving, 1952-1966, n.d.; 48 items (Box 13)
    Publications; administrative matters in the Yale Department of Anthropology.
  - Rowe, John H., 1952-1964; 4 items (Box 13)
    Classification problems in the Arawak family; bibliographical references for FGL; FGL's planned visit to San Francisco and UC Berkeley; inviting FGL to join the Anthropology Department at UC Berkeley.
  - Rubin, Joan, 1961-1972; 15 items (Box 14)
    Rubin's dissertation on bilingualism in Paraguay (Guarani and Spanish); grants; teaching positions.
  - Ruby, Denise, 1969; 1 item (Box 14)
    Kinship terminology.
  - Rudes, Blair A., 1977-1995; 13 items (Box 14)
    Rudes' work on Tuscarora; teaching positions. Includes: photocopy typescripts of Rudes' "More on the Terminology of Tense, Mood, and Aspect in Northern Iroquoian Descriptions" and his morphological analysis of 7 Tuscarora texts collect by Anthony F. C. Wallace.
  - Ruggles, Clive, 1989; 2 items (Box 14)
    Third International Conference on Archaeoastronomy.
  - Ruhlen, Merritt, 1978-1981; 2.0 Item(s) (Box 14)
  - Rushton, Daley, 1950; 2 items (Box 14)
    FGL's work on the WPA Oneida language project.
  - Ruz Lhuillier, Alberto, 1965; 2 items (Box 14)
    Obtaining a copy of Desarrollo de la Cultura Maya; soliciting material from FGL and colleagues ethnographic and social anthropological material for the series Estudios de Cultura Maya. In English and Spanish.
  - Saffo, Paul Laurence, 1976; 2 items (Box 14)
    Mayan term for zero.
  - Salovesh, Michael, 1973; 1 item (Box 14)
  - Salwen, Bert, 1961; 1 item (Box 14)
    Thevet's description of Maine coast Indians; Salwen's work on the prehistory of southern New England.
  - Salzinger, Kurt, 1962-1965; 3 items (Box 14)
    A conference on verbal behavior.
  - Sam, Archie, 1980-1983; 2 items (Box 14)
    Obtaining copies of recordings of Watt and Martin Sam made by FGL at Braggs, Oklahoma in 1939.
  - Samuelson, Clifford L., 1961; 4 items (Box 14)
    Special tutoring in linguistics by FGL to help prepare Robert Greene for work with Native Americans in the continental U. S.
  - Sapir, Edward, 1936-1937; 23 pcs. (Box 14)
    Reports and accounts for field work from Blyth (Northern Paiutes), Cooke (Northern Utes), La Barre (peyote, Oklahoma), Osgood (Puerto Rico), Smith (Kalispel), and Zigmond (Kawaiisu). From folder: "Yale Students Field Work Reports and Accounts"
  - Saporta, Sol, and Samuel E. Martin, 1962; 2 items (Box 14)
    FGL's participation in the 1963 Linguistic Institute.
  - Sargent, Margaret, 1949-1950; 4 items (Box 14)
    The whereabouts of 39 Iroquois records collected in 1912 at Grand River, Ontario, by A. A. Goldenweiser.
  - Scancarelli, Janine, 1984-1994; 10 items (Box 14)
    Scancarelli's work on Cherokee. Includes photocopies of her papers "Pragmatic Roles in Cherokee Grammar" and "Variation and Change in Cherokee: Evidence from the Pronominal Prefixes."
  - Scarf, Herbert E., 1989; 1 item (Box 14)
    Proposed nomination of Martin Shubik for membership in the National Academy of Sciences.
  - Schaedel, Richard P., 1947-1953; 29 items (Box 14)
    Schaedel's work and travel in Peru; Peruvian archaeology; shipping books, etc. to Peru; Quechua language; work on Mochik or Yunga (Chipaya); FGL's planned trip (1950) to Mato Grosso; failure to find Mochik speakers in La Villa de Eten; FGL's and Schaedel's proposed business venture in Mato Grosso; teaching in Chile.
  - Scheffler, Hal W., 1965-1974, n.d.; 16 items (Box 14)
    Kinship systems; Siriono kinship; Scheffler's work on Baniata (Central Melanesian) language and ethnography. Includes: carbon copy manuscript of FGL and H. W. Scheffler "Siriono Matriliny: Ethnographic Fact or Analytical Fiction?"
  - Schele, Linda, 1981-1991; 3 items (Box 14)
    The death of Bob Robertson in Mexico City and establishing a memorial fund in his honor; permission for FGL to publish her Palenque drawings.
  - Schilling, Carol S., 1962-1963; 5 items (Box 14)
    Schilling's work on Onondaga; kinship systems, particularly Apinaye (Ge).
  - Schlak, Arthur, 1984-1995; 37 items (Box 14)
    Maya calendrics and astronomy with particular attention to Venus, Mercury, and Mars; employment.
  - Schneider, David M., 1962-1971; 18 items (Box 14)
    Kinship systems with mention of Crow and Omaha, Zuni, Apinaye, Classical Latin, Yucatec Maya, Kariera, Quechua, Trobriand, Pawnee, and Seriono.
  - Schuster, Carl, 1967-1968; 13 items (Box 14)
    Skin robes (Australian and Bororo), the Ainu inao; metaphorical use of terms for plants or plant parts in genealogical and kinship nomenclature. Includes: photographs of Bororo jaguar skin robes; drawings of ceramics from Machu Pichu and northwest Argentina.
  - Schwab, William B., 1988; 1 item (Box 14)
    A proposal to organize an Association of Retired Professors as a sub-unit of AAA.
  - Sebeok, Thomas A., 1950-1958; 22 items (Box 14)
    Sebeok's and FGL's work on Aymara; a proposed psycholinguistic study of the clustering of consonants; papers from a conference on style in language.
  - Senner, W. M., 1994; 3 items (Box 14)
    A paper to be given by FGL on ancient writing in Middle America. Includes a photocopy of Keith N. Schoville, "Communication across Time and Space: The Origins of Writing."
  - Severin, Gregory, 1977-1978; 4 items (Box 14)
    Mayan calendars and the interpretation of certain elements of the Paris codex.
  - Shapiro, Warren, 1964; 3 items (Box 14)
    Bororo kinship; planned field work on kinship among the Komaiura (Comayura) of the Upper Xingu Basin.
  - Sharpe, Myron E., 1962; 7 items (Box 14)
    Possible members (including FGL) of an advisory committee for a proposed journal, Soviet Anthropology and Archeology.
  - Shelley, George L., III, 1977; 1 item (Box 14)
    Expressing reciprocity in Dukai (Rukai) (Austronesian).
  - Sherwood, David, 1978-1980, n.d.; 9 items (Box 14)
    Sherwood's dissertation, "Maliseet-Passamaquoddy Inflectional Morphology and Syntax"; grant application. Includes a photocopy of Sherwood's "Bibliography: Descriptive and Historical Linguistics."
  - Shimony, Annemarie, 1953-1996, n.d.; 35 items (Box 14)
    Her ethnographic work on the Six Nations Reserve, Ontario. Includes a cassette recording of a 1996 memorial session after her death.
  - Shipley, William F., 1963-1967; 7 items (Box 14)
    Arranging for FGL to speak at the UC Berkeley Linguistics Group.
  - Siebert, Frank T., 1979; 1 item (Box 14)
    Observations on meetings of the Linguistic Society of America and Transformational Grammar; etymology of Tuscarora; Cherokee and Catawba terms for each other; Maliseet-Passamaquoddy.
  - Siegel, Bernard J., 1958-1961, n.d.; 8 items (Box 14)
    FGL's chapter on linguistics for The Review of Anthropological Literature. Includes carbon copies of drafts of bibliographies and comments for FGL's contribution.
  - Sills, David L., 1963-1965; 14 items (Box 14)
    FGL's contributions to International Encyclopedia of the Social Sciences.
  - Silverstein, Michael, 1983; 4 items (Box 14)
    Special issue(s) of IJAL honoring Eric Hamp. Includes a bibliography of Hamp's publications.
  - Sion, Edward M., 1984; 1 item (Box 14)
    Inquiring whether the Maya recorded any nova or supernova events.
  - Skenandore, John A., 1940-1942; 6 items (Box 15)
    Music, musicians, designing and building a new musical instrument; personal and family matters. One letter and one postal card in Oneida.
  - Skenandore, Paul A., 1974; 1 item (Box 15)
    Inquiring whether FGL has published a study of the Oneida language.
  - Smiley, Charles H., 1967-1974; 10 items (Box 15)
    Mayan astronomy and meteorology.
  - Snow, Dean R., 1988-1994; 4 items (Box 15)
    Lists of Iroquois conference participants. Includes a list of 1988 participants.
  - Social Science Research Council, 1954-1964; 53 items (Box 15)
    Business of the Committee on Linguistics and Psychology; a proposed Brazilian project to document native languages; conference on verbal style; proposed reader in psycholinguistics; grants; summer research seminar on aphasia.
  - Sociological Abstracts, Inc., 1966; 3 items (Box 15)
    FGL's abstract of his article on formal analysis of kinship terms.
  - Spain, Rufus B., 1966; 5 items (Box 15)
    The availability for purchase of a manuscript in the Cherokee syllabary. Includes photocopies of 2 pages from the manuscript.
  - Spaulding, Albert C., 1961-1963, n.d.; 10 items (Box 15)
    FGL's service on the advisory panel for Anthropology and History and Philosophy of Science of the Division of Social Sciences of the NSF.
  - Spier, Leslie, 1937-1938; 45 pp; 2 photos (Box 15)
    Reports and accounts for fieldwork from Blythe (Paiute), Cook (Northern Ute), Haas (Creek, Hitchiti, Choctaw), Mandelbaum (India), Osgood (Northern Athapascans, Alaska), Rouse (Puerto Rico), Siebert (Penobscot), Smith (Kalispel) including photos of consultants, Trager (Taos), and Zigmond (Kawaiisu).
  - Spindler, George D., 1964-1965; 5 items (Box 15)
    FGL's possible contribution to a new series on methods and techniques in anthropology.
  - Stark, Louisa R., 1967-1972; 12 items (Box 15)
    Obtaining data on Yunga; similarities between Yunga and Mayan languages; possible relation of the Ge-Bororo group to Mayan; possible affinities of Saliva with Yunga; surface similarities between Quechua and Mayan. Includes a manuscript copy of Stark's "Mayan Affinities with Araucanian"; Vol. 3, No. 1 (January 1972) of "Andean Linguistics Newsletter."
  - Starna, William A., 1988, n.d.; 5 items (Box 15)
    Use of the term "dog" in northern Iroquoian languages particularly with regard to slaves. Includes a list of terms in an unidentified language (possibly northern Iroquoian) with English glosses pertaining to animals, slaves, and abuse.
  - Starr, M. Kenneth, 1957-1994; 6 items (Box 15)
    Starr's election to Sigma Xi; personal matters.
  - Steckley, John, 1982; 2 items (Box 15)
    Huron forms which reflect the Cherokee "ne" rather than Northern Iroquoian "wi."
  - Stefansson, Vilhjalmur, 1959-1960; 2 items (Box 15)
    William Dwight Whitney's attitude toward "primitive languages."
  - Steffire, Volney, 1965, n.d.; 2 items (Box 15)
    Apurar (appurar) paraphrase matrices.
  - Steinberg, Danny D., 1968; 3 items (Box 15)
    Discussion of FGL's and other contributions to an interdisciplinary reader in semantics.
  - Stimson, Hugh M., 1962, n.d.; 3 items (Box 15)
    Stimson's work on Shanghai with extensive discussion. Includes transcripts and translations of some poetry.
  - Stone, Frederick L., 1968; 1 item (Box 15)
    Inviting FGL to serve a 4-year term on the Behavioral Sciences Training Committee, NIH.
  - Stothers, David M., 1987; 6 items (Box 15)
    The meaning of the tribal name Kovatocronon. Includes maps and articles relating to the prehistory of the western Lake Erie region.
  - Straight, H. Stephen, 1970; 3 items (Box 15)
    A proposed symposium on Mayan languages at the Sixth Regional Meeting of the Chicago Linguistic Society.
  - Stratman-Thomas, Helene, 1947-1948, n.d.; 6 items (Box 15)
    Oneida hymns.
  - Street, John C., 1964-1976; 3 items (Box 15)
    Nayer (South India) kinship system; Maya hieroglyphs.
  - Strouthes, Daniel, 1994; 3 items (Box 15)
    Recommendations; a humorous incident on the Micmac reserve.
  - Stuart, George, 1986; 2.0 Item(s) (Box 15)
  - Sturtevant, William C., 1951-1994, n.d.; 137 items (3 folders) (Box 15)
    Sturtevant's work on Muskogean; his work on the language and ethnography of the Seminole; publications and papers; Iroquois culture; Iroquois conferences; glottochronology; grant applications; Sturtevant's work with Oklahoma Seneca-Cayuga; Natchez social structure; Pamunkey numbers; Northern Iroquois section of the Handbook of North American Indians; recording of Creek songs issued by the Library of Congress. Includes: Sturtevant's notebook of vocabulary items from Timucua, Muscogean, Arawak, and some Carib; carbon copy manuscript Of Sturtevant's "Notes on Ritual Siblinghood in the Seneca Nation"; carbon copy notes by Sturtevant of Merle H. Deardorff's "The Indians and the Kinzua Dam"; photocopy of part of a manuscript by Anna Gritts Kilpatrick and Jack Frederick Kilpatrick "Chronicles of Wolftown: Social documents of the North Carolina Cherokees, 1850-1862"; photocopy of Gordon M. Day, "Iroquois: An Etymology."
  - Swadesh, Frances Leon, 1964; 1 item (Box 15)
    Swadesh's work on Otomi.
  - Swadesh, Morris, 1939-1964, n.d.; 34 items (Box 15)
    The Caughnawaga Iroquois in Brooklyn, NY; the Wisconsin Oneida language project; Swadesh's activities in Mexico; Tarascan literacy project; problems of education of natives in their languages; FGL's work on Oneida and Cherokee; FGL's being drafted into the Army; Swadesh's work on genetic classification of Native American languages; Swadesh's placement of Tarascan in the Penutian phylum by way of Quechua-Aymara; deciphering Maya hieroglyphs. Includes: sample pages of a hymnal probably in Mohawk; copies of documents "Plan del projyecto tarasco," "Acta de la primera asamblea de filologos y linguistas de Mexico," and "Proyecto de estatutos del Instituto Indigenista Mexicano"; basic vocabulary lists in Osage and Oneida.
  - Szabo, George, 1967; 2 items (Box 15)
    Possible relationships of the "Ural-Altay" groups to other languages.
  - Szczerba-Likiernik, K., 1966; 1 item (Box 15)
    A symposium in Paris on cross-cultural research tools and possible participants.
  - Taack, George H., 1973-1977; 6 items (Box 15)
    Taack's attempted readings of the "Hunting Section" of Codex Madrid using Knorozov; FGL's unwillingness to assign readings to most of the Maya glyphs in the text; FGL's opinion of Knorozov's work.
  - Takaki, Michiko, 1968-1981, n.d.; 22 items (Box 15)
    Her dissertation on "A Study of Exchange Systems in a Kalinga Community" (Northern Luzon, the Philippines; grant application. Includes: photocopy of her paper "Capital Management in a Kalinga Society: Conveyance and Conversion."
  - Tax, Sol, 1953-1972; 28 items (Box 15)
    Current Anthropology; AAA matters; reviews of articles and books
  - Taylor, Douglas, 1948-1969; 10 items (Box 15)
    Taylor's work on Cariban and Arawakan; problems of stress and vowel length in Arawak (Lokono). Includes: Comparative vocabulary for 'man', 'woman', 'wife', 'mother', 'drink', 'blood', and 'juice' in various Arawakan and Cariban languages.
  - Thomas, Leta, 1961; 2 items (Box 16)
    Requesting information on publications regarding the Ojibwa and Indian treaties.
  - Thomas, Robert K., 1963; 3 items (Box 16)
    Finding a linguist to work on a cross-cultural education project to teach the reading of English; FGL's renewed interest in Cherokee.
  - Thompson, Laurence C., 1958-1980; 4 items (Box 16)
    Thompson's work on a Vietnamese reader; his work on Thompson Salish.
  - Thompson, Raymond H., 1958; 2 items (Box 16)
    A proposed article by FGL critical of Knorozov's work on Maya hieroglyphs.
  - Thord-Gray, I, 1956; 3 items (Box 16)
    Thord-Gray's Tarahumara dictionary; how he became interested in the Tarahumara.
  - Tilman, R. O., 1968; 3 items (Box 16)
    A proposed cooperative arrangement in the social sciences among Yale and 2 Southeast Asian universities; FGL's reactions.
  - Tilney, A. G., 1952; 1 item (Box 16)
    FGL's work on Bororo; Tilney's ideas about the origin of human speech.
  - Todorov, Tzvetan, 1965-1967; 6 items (Box 16)
    The translation into French of FGL's "The Structural Analysis of Kinship Semantics" for publication; Todorov's one-year appointment as visiting professor of French at Yale. Includes a carbon copy of the French translation of FGL's article.
  - Todorova, Vera, 1996; 1 item (Box 16)
    FGL's comments on Kilpatrick's manuscript, "The Night has a Naked Soul: Witchcraft and Sorcery among the Western Cherokee."
  - Tol, Hendrika, 1960-1961; 19 items (Box 16)
    Tol's work on Arekuna (Arecuna / Carib) in British Guiana as a non-linguist; FGL's advice on how to proceed and kinds of data of interest to anthropologists. Includes basic vocabulary and kinship charts for Arekuna and Acawai (Carib).
  - Tooker, Elizabeth, 1959-1992; 40 items (Box 16)
    Tooker's work on Huron; Iroquois conferences; Seneca kinship terminologies (includes data); Iroquois cosmology.
  - Trager, George L., 1954-1966; 4 items (Box 16)
    FGL's Oneida Verb Morphology; the situation in the Department of Anthropology at the University of Buffalo; possible teaching positions.
  - Trigger, Bruce G., 1967-1976; 3 items (Box 16)
    The Northeast volume of the Handbook of North American Indians.
  - Tri-institutional Pacific Program (TRIP), 1953-1957, n.d.; 30 items (Box 16)
    Historical linguistics and genetic classification of languages; kinds of data desired for the program; vocabulary lists.
  - Trimble, Lee S., 1952; 1 item (Box 16)
    Possible origin of the name 'Tallapoosa' as being a Muskogean language but not Cherokee or other Iroquoian language.
  - Troike, Nancy, 1977-1988; 5 items (Box 16)
    Seminars on Maya hieroglyphic writing; notes on 'Palenque "9-16-9" phrases'.
  - Tschopik, Harry, Jr., 1948-1952; 16 items (Box 16)
    FGL's analysis of Aymara texts collected by Tschopik; Aymara material collected by Thomas Sebeok; Bororo movies made by Cutlow; recordings of Eastern Woodland music.
  - Tulchin, Joseph, 1964; 1 item (Box 16)
    Information on Quechua, Aymara, Guarani, and Mayan languages including geographic distribution, population, availability of pedagogical materials, etc.
  - Twaddell, W. Freeman, 1958; 2 items (Box 16)
    An ACLS survey of language needs and facilities in connection with the National Defense Education Act.
  - Tyler, Ralph W., 1963-1964; 5 items (Box 16)
    FGL's year as a fellow at the Center for Advanced Study in the Behavioral Sciences.
  - Tyler, Stephen A., 1967-1968; 4 items (Box 16)
    Corrections and suggested changes to copy being readied for publication.
  - Ullrich, Helen, 1963; 1 item (Box 16)
    Revisions to her paper on Havik Brahmin kinship.
  - Unidentified, 1949-1998, n.d.; 228 items (3 folders) (Box 16)
    Letters, drawings, photographs, etc. without identification or having only partial identification. Personal communications; Mayan studies; Endangered Language Fund; meetings and conferences; Oneida language and kinship; various kinship systems; publications; South American languages; etc.
  - University of Wisconsin, 1941-1959; 26 items (Box 16)
    Expense reports, etc. for FGL's work on the Oneida Language Project; the death of Professor John L. Gillen.
  - Utley, Francis Lee, 1967; 3 items (Box 16)
    A proposal to establish an American Placename Survey. Includes a draft copy of the proposal.
  - Vakar, Nicholas P., 1954; 1 item (Box 17)
  - Vallee, Frank G., 1961; 4 items (Box 17)
    Conference on Iroquoian Studies at McMaster University.
  - Venetianer, Sid, 1952-1989; 6 items (Box 17)
    FGL's marriage; family news; FGL's first heart attack.
  - Ventur, Pierre Erich, 1972-1995, n.d.; 85 items (2 folders) (Box 17)
    Ventur's graduate study at Yale, grant applications, field work in Guatemala, and dissertation.
  - Verin, Pierre, 1964, n.d.; 2 items (Box 17)
    Some pamphlets sent for Bernard Bloch; Verin's work on Merina (Malagasy), particularly kinship terms; Verin's work in Madagascar.
  - Vermont Salas, Refugio, 1969-1974, n.d.; 16 items (Box 17)
    Financial support for Vermont S. to continue his education.
  - Vestal, Mrs. A., 1981-1982; 4 items (Box 17)
    Finding publications on the Maya calendar.
  - Villela, Khris, 1991; 1 item (Box 17)
    The interpretation of some Maya glyphs on the Palenque stairway.
  - Voegelin, Carl F., 1947-1981; 89 items (Box 17)
    Expressing terms such as "lethargy" and "nirvana" in Iroquoian and Algonquian languages; meanings of place names; Joint Committee on American Native Languages; IJAL; a manuscript "Iroquois" grammar; experience and technique for magnetic and phonographic recording of languages in the 1940's; use of Native American language material in college courses; FGL's observations on Bororo and Krao similarities and possible genetic relationship of Bororo to Ge; Linguistic Institute at Indiana University; publication of FGL's dissertation; 1952 conference of anthropologists and linguists. Includes copies of some of Voegelin's correspondence with: Kenneth L. Pike, Evon Z. Vogt, Jr., Margaret Mead, Paul L. Garvin, William L. Wonderly, Harry Hoijer, Isidore Dyen, and Rulon Wells.
  - Voegelin, Florence M., 1966-1979; 3 items (Box 17)
    Anthropological Linguistics.
  - Voget, Fred, 1960; 2 items (Box 17)
    Iroquois studies.
  - Vogt, Evon Z., Jr., 1953-1993; 10 items (Box 17)
    A proposed AAAS symposium on culture change; a proposed symposium on the Mayan civilization.
  - Voorhies, Barbara, 1984; 3 items (Box 17)
    The interpretation of symbols on an Aztec artifact. Includes a picture and discussion.
  - Voorhis, Paul, 1964-1967, n.d.; 24 items (Box 17)
    Voorhis' work on Kickapoo (Fox) with discussion of the language and consultants.
  - Wagner, Laura, 1994; 2 items (Box 17)
    Discussion of some points of grammar raised in her work on Oneida.
  - Walker, Donald E., 1954-1984; 5 items (Box 17)
    Trying to establish a program in Anthropology at Rice University; Association for Computational Linguistics.
  - Walker, Willard B., 1963-1991; 10 items (Box 17)
    Job possibilities; Walker's work on Cherokee.
  - Wallace, Anthony F. C., 1949-1964; 19 items (Box 17)
    Wallace's Tuscarora materials; Wallace's paper on Maya art; Iroquois conference; Wallace's paper on the Dekanawideh myth; componential analysis of kinship terms.
  - Walters, Joel F., 1965, n.d.; 4 items (Box 17)
    FGL's comments on a manuscript.
  - Wang, William S-Y., 1964; 2 items (Box 17)
    Availability of FGL's materials on Wu (Chinese).
  - Wann, T. W., 1960; 1 item (Box 17)
    Finding personnel for staffing at The Rice Institute.
  - Wanyula, Phil, 1989-1990; 31 items (Box 17)
    Personal matters; Texas Copan Workshop. Includes 27 color photographs of people including FGL who are possibly participants in the Texas Copan Workshop.
  - Watson, James B., 1957-1963; 3 items (Box 17)
    A paper on dogs in a Tibetan camp; Bororo settlement patterns.
  - Watson, Roy E. L., 1964; 2 items (Box 17)
    Adding a linguistics course in the anthropology program at the University of Victoria.
  - Waukesha High School, 1987; 3 items (Box 17)
    The 55th reunion of the class of 1932. Includes a list of class members.
  - Waxman, Cathy, 1972; 20 items (Box 17)
    Expense report for travel to Red Hook, New York, and Oneida consultant salary.
  - Wedel, Mildred M., 1959; 1 item (Box 17)